Just like bread companies make copies of the starter from their mother dough,
就像面包公司通过老面团来复制原始配方
every Spark function makes a copy of its input data
每个 Spark 函数都会复制一份输入数据
and never changes the original parent data.
从而保证原始数据不会改变
Because Spark doesn't change or mutate the input data,
因为 Spark 不会更改输入数据
it's known as immutible.
它被称为不可变的（immutible）
This makes sense when you have a single function.
这种方式对于单独的函数是行得通的
But what happens when you have lots of functions in your program?
但是当你的程序中有很多函数时会发生什么呢
After all, there are usually a lot of steps when you wrangle data,
毕竟 当你处理数据时 通常会有很多步骤
just like there are many steps in baking bread.
就像烤面包有很多步骤一样
In Spark, you do this by chaining together multiple functions
在 Spark 中 你也需要通过多个函数一起来处理数据
that each accomplish a small chunk of the work.
每个函数完成一小部分工作
You'll often see a function that is composed of multiple subfunctions,
很多函数都由一堆子函数组成
and in order for this big function to be peer,
所以要使这个大函数工作
each sub function also has to be peer.
每个子函数就需要随时待命
It would seem that Spark needs to make a copy
似乎这种方式下 Spark 需要
of the input data for each subfunction.
为每个子函数复制一份输入数据
If this was the case, your Spark program
如果是这种情况 那 Spark 程序
would run out of memory pretty quickly.
很快就会耗尽内存
Fortunately, Spark avoids this by using
还好 Spark 会通过一种叫
a functional programming concept called lazy evaluation.
惰性计算的函数式编程概念来避免这种情况的发生
Before Spark does anything with the data in your program,
在 Spark 对程序中的数据进行任何操作前
it first built step-by-step directions of what functions and data it will need.
它首先会建立一个流程图 把每步所需的函数和数据确定好
These directions are like the recipe for your bread,
流程图每个步骤中的指引就像你的面包配方
and in Spark, this is called a Directed Acyclic Graph.
在 Spark 中 这个流程图称为有向无环图
Now, that's a mouthful.
听上去很拗口
So almost everyone just uses the abbreviation DAG.
所以几乎每个人都使用它的缩写 DAG（Directed Acyclic Graph）
Once Spark builds the DAG from your code,
当 Spark 在代码上构建 DAG
it checks if it can procrastinate,
它会检查是否可以暂时不复制数据
waiting until the last possible moment to get the data.
等到最后一刻再去复制数据
This is exactly what you would do if you were baking bread.
这正是你在烤面包时会做的事情
You want to grab the flour, bring it back to your bowl,
你不会抓完面粉 把它带回碗里
and then go back to the pantry and get some sugar and add it to the bowl,
然后又回到厨房拿糖 再回去加入碗里
and then go back to the cupboard for salt,
然后又回到柜子里取盐
and so on for every ingredient.
然后每使用一次原料就再重复一次上面的步骤
This would be the cooking equivalent of thrashing as we discussed in lesson one.
和第一课中说的数据颠簸一样 这种来回取原料的方式非常浪费时间
Instead, you would look at the recipe before you start mixing
事实上 你会在开始作面团之前就查看配方
ingredients together to see what you can grab and mix together in one big step.
看看你可以先把哪些原料一次性混在一起
In fact, you often mix all your dry ingredients,
通常 你会把所有的干原料混合
then mix all your wet ingredients,
然后混合所有湿原料
and then combine them together before baking.
最后在烘烤前将它们混合在一起
In Spark, these multi-step combos are called stages.
在 Spark 中 这些多步组合称为阶段